A Guide to the Elizabeth C. Denny Vann and Margaret C. Denny Dixon Papers, 1920-1977
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Elizabeth C. Denny Vann and Margaret C. Denny Dixon Papers, 1920-1977
The Library of Virginia
29981
11.25 cubic feet (28 boxes)
Vann, Elizabeth C. Denny, 1884-1977.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The material was deposited by Mrs. E. C. Denny Vann, Richmond, Virginia, 10 December 1975, and by her son, Dr. Felix H. Vann, Englewood, New Jersey, 1 June 1977 and 8 June 1978.
Biographical Information
Elizabeth C. Denny Vann (1884-1977) and her sister Margaret C. Denny Dixon (1882-1964) were genealogists and authors who were also active in civic affairs in Richmond, Virginia. The result of their research can be seen in four books which they coauthored. These books were the following: Denny Genealogy, 3 vols. (1944-1951); Brumback-Hotsinpiller Genealogy (1961), and also a pamphlet, Virginia's First German Colony [Germanna] (1961). In addition to publishing the results of their research the sisters made numerous public appearances, such as the annual Germanna Family Reunions, in order to keep in contact with their relatives.
Scope and Content
This collection includes the genealogical correspondence and research of Elizabeth C. Denny Vann (1884-1977) and her sister Margaret C. Denny Dixon (1882-1964). The research is primarily concerned with the Brumback-Hotsinpiller and the Denny family lines. The material was compiled through extensive research in county records and by correspondence with genealogists and family members throughout the United States and England. The bulk of this collection contains the incoming correspondence to the two sisters.
Contents List
- Elizabeth C. Denny Vann and Margaret C. Denny Dixon Papers, 1920-1977., Extent: 28 boxes and 1 oversize folder. (Box 1-28)
  - (Box 1)
    - Addresses and publication finances
    - Allied miscellaneous lines
    - James Blythe Anderson
    - Sabina Surbaugh Anderson
    - Anderson-Denny
    - R. G. Arthur, Delaware Dennys
    - Margaret Hubbard Bailey and Harriet Lucinda Hubbard Hunter
    - Sarah Lockhart Baker
    - Baville-Champion
    - Blacker-Hotspiller families
    - Dr. Fritz Braun
    - Brumbach and Hotsenspiller sources
    - Correspondence about pictures, Brumbach-Hotsenspiller
    - Publicity on Brumback-Hotsinpiller genealogy, reviews on Denny genealogies
    - Brumback-Hotsinpiller genealogy, promotional literature
    - Subscribers to the Brumback-Hotsinpiller genealogy, corrections and additions
    - Comments on Brumback-Hotsinpiller genealogy from subscribers, and the Germanna booklet
  - (Box 2)
    - 1960's correspondence to Margaret D. Dixon and Elizabeth C. D. Vann regarding Brumback-Hotsinpiller genealogy and the Germanna booklet, Virginia's First German Colony
    - Brumbach-Hotsenpillar and 1st Colony correspondence
    - Michael Bunger
    - Michael Bunger source material, the Kerr family, Anthony Hutsinpillar
    - Burke - Encyclopedia of Heraldry, photostats
    - Jean Burns
    - Campbell daughters
    - Campbell sons
    - Ollie Carpenter
    - Collins family, Somerset County
    - Correspondence with Collins regarding Mathie Rawlins Estate
    - Correspondence about publishing a book
    - Crum, Smith, and Affleck families
  - (Box 3)
    - Christopher Harrison Denny
    - Denny, Columbia, Pennsylvania
    - Denny of Combs, Suffolk, England
    - David Denny Sr.
    - David Denny Sr., source material
    - Sons of David - Nathan Denny - John Denny
    - Deborah Susanna Denny
    - Delaware Dennys
    - Source material on various Denny emigrants through the Port of Philadelphia
    - Denny family
    - Denny family papers
    - Denny family tree, photographs
  - (Box 4)
    - Denny family source material
    - Additional information - Book I, Denny Genealogy
    - Denny Genealogy 1944, 1st book
    - Denny Genealogy, 2nd book, 1st part
    - Denny Genealogy, 3rd book, promotional folders, Some Old Friends of Saint Andrew Undershaft by Rev. Sir Henry L. L. Denny
    - Source material for Denny Genealogy, third book by Dixon and Vann, 1951, Dennys of Seattle
    - Denny Genealogy, third book
    - Arms and Heraldry, Overseas - Denny Genealogy
    - Denny Genealogy, folders 1-2
  - (Box 5)
    - Denny Genealogy, folder 3
    - Elisha T. Denny, Morris T. Denny, Mary Denny
    - Frederick Denny line
    - Guy Denney
    - World War II articles by Harold Denny
    - Denny inquiries
    - C. C. Denny, New England Denny
    - New Jersey - Denny
    - Sir J. Lionel Percy Denny, personal correspondence, Collins Denny material
    - Isabel Denny
    - Isabella Denny
    - James Denny, William H. Denny
    - James Denny of Kentucky 1802, Dr. Fred Denny, Mrs. Bessie Rea
    - James Denny, Talbot County Maryland, John Frazer Jr., Philadelphia, Pa.
    - John Denny
    - John Denny, Arthur A. Denny
    - John Denny, David Thomas Denny
    - John Denny, Allen Wiley Denny
    - John Denny, Alfred Wilson Denny
  - (Box 6)
    - John Denny, John Fletcher Denny
    - John Denny of Seattle
    - Joseph Denny
    - Margaret Denny Davis
    - Margaret Hotsenpiller Denny, Joseph S. Denny
    - Margaret Parsons Denny
    - Maria Ann Denny
    - Mary T. Denny Stone, James Denny, Sarah Mars Denny
    - Oregon line - Denny family
    - Dr. R. B. Denny
    - Rachel Denny, Judge Robert Denny
    - Rachel Denny
  - (Box 7)
    - Robert Denny, David Denny
    - Robert Steers Denny
    - Samuel Denny, Joel Shields Denny, John Miles Denny, and Lewis Woody Denny
    - Samuel Denny, Henry Levi Denny
    - Samuel Denny
    - Samuel Denny daughters, Elizabeth Denny Sloan and Mary Ann Denny Grimes Stomaday
    - Samuel Denny, John William Denny
    - Samuel Denny, Sarah Louisa Denny Baker
    - Samuel Denny, Josephine L. Denny McCombs
    - Samuel Denny, Thomas Goffe Denny
    - Samuel Denny, Samuel Thomas Denny
    - Thomas Hedger Denny
    - Walter Denny, folder 1
  - (Box 8)
    - Walter Denny, folder 2
    - Walter Denny of Mississippi
    - Walter Denny line, Elizabeth Denny Sharp
    - Col. Wm. H. D. Denny (Beulah, Miss.)
    - Letters - Genealogical Society of Utah, galley proof - William Denny Part I of Denny Genealogy - 2nd book
    - William Denny of Newton, Descendants of Elizabeth Mytinger and Linna Jordan
    - William Denny of Newton, William R. Denny
    - William Denny, Ebenezer Denny, and Martha McClure, folder 1
  - (Box 9)
    - William Denny, Ebenezer Denny, and Martha McClure, folders 2-3
    - William R. Denny
    - Disposition of Ohio land
    - Dixon and Vann, fan mail
    - Helen Eckert
    - Estate receipts in Ohio
  - (Box 10)
    - Eliza Denny Gaither, John Denny Gaither
    - John Denny Gaither
    - Dr. C. H. Huffman, Germanna
    - Germanna inquiries
    - Agnes Johnson, Hinton, West Virginia; Germanna
    - Tom McMasters, Germanna
    - Printed material regarding Germanna
    - Germanna, review copies and publicity
    - Germanna sources
    - Margaret Denny Lockhart Gore
    - Intermarriages - Greenbrier
    - Isabel Ann Hubbard Guthrie
    - Harry Handley, M. D. correspondence, also Hutsenpillar information
    - Hatzenbuehler and unidentified
    - Mrs. Sumner Haywood
    - Heffernan
    - Eliza Gaither Higbee
    - Hite family
    - James Denny Hollis
    - Holtzclaw
    - Christina Hotsebieler [Rudolph]
    - Seigle Hotsenpillar
    - Hotsenpiller
  - (Box 11)
    - George, son of Stephen Hotsenpiller
    - Jacob, son of Stephen Hotsenpiller
    - Hotsenpiller, Niswanger, Ancestors of Carleton Powell
    - Sarah Hotsenpiller Thompson, George Hotsenpiller
    - Stephen, son of Stephen Hotsenpiller Jr.
    - Hotsenpiller sources
    - Stephen the Emigrant, shipping lists material, Hotsenpiller
    - John Hotsinpiller Sr., son of Stephen
    - Benjamin Hotzenpiller - Jacob - Stephen - Anthony
    - Nancy Behethlin Hubbard
    - William Austin Hubbard
    - Inquiries from Mrs. Frank Hughes
    - Hutsen - Indiana
    - John, Jacob, Stephen. Sidney Hutsen, Hutsenpillar family
    - John Hutsenpiller
    - David, son of Abraham Hutsenpiller
  - (Box 12)
    - Abraham Hutsin Piller
    - Hutsinpiller family
    - Henry and Rachel Hutsinpiller
    - Jacob, son of Anthony, William Hutsinpiller
    - Hutsonpiller correspondence
    - Indices
    - Investment record
    - Kercheval suit
    - Fred and Elizabeth Kessler, daughter Sarah McCutcheon, daughter Catharine Campbell, and all the Campbells
    - Mrs. Nellie Kirby, Portland, Oregon
    - Libby Krebs' notes on the Denny family
    - Louisa Maria Hubbard Lee
    - Lemley, Crum Smith, Afflick
  - (Box 13)
    - Source material, John Lewis, Sally Viola McCutcheon Fitzwater, Newton O. McCutcheon
    - Library lists
    - Martha Matilda Hubbard Litton
    - Josiah Lockhart, Margery Wilson Lockhart
    - Margery Denny Wilson Lockhart, source material
    - Thomas Jefferson Lockhart
    - Mc C. ______ Knox
    - Allen McCutcheon
    - Henry McCutcheon, source material
    - McCutcheon-Michaels, source material
    - McCutcheon-Neil
    - Permilia Denny Martin
    - Mecorney-Nisbet
    - Mrs. E. V. Miller
    - Miscellaneous: 1930, 1931, 1932
  - (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous genealogical notes
    - Rebecca Nisbet
    - Publicity about Elizabeth C. D. Vann and Margaret C. D. Dixon, regarding Denny Genealogies
    - Some early Ohio and Pennsylvania families, Burns Part, by Carle L. Maskey, source for Denny Genealogy 1944, first book
    - Matilda Hotsenpiller Phillips
    - Pictures, postcards, pamphlets, etc.
    - Prairie Pioneers -- Martindale and Lunsford Families by Alta Martindale Pressnell, Denny Genealogy Book III
    - Mrs. Esther Weygandt Powell, 36 N. Highland Avenue, Akron, Ohio
    - Ransbarger family
    - Isaac Rawlings family
    - Mary Ann Rawlins and descendants, also Martha A. F. H. Mayne
    - Rawlings papers, Seigle Hotsenpiller land
    - Records of subscriptions to all books
    - Amos Davis Rector
    - Rector duplicates
    - Elizabeth S. Hotsenpiller Rector
  - (Box 15)
    - Elizabeth Martha Rector, Henry Clay Rector
    - John R. Rector
    - The Rector Family of Pickaway County, The Push to the West by Helen Eckert
    - Rector family
    - Rector reunions and family pictures, Helen Eckert
    - Spencer Rector
    - Rector-Wiggins-Terwilleger-Rose reunion
    - Andrew L. Riffe IV correspondence
    - Ritenour and Marker families
    - Ruth Ritterbush
    - Fannie Mae Scales, 8 Magnolia Drive, Mary Esther, Fla. 32569
    - Dr. Charles Frederick Seigle, sources
    - Seigle-Hotsenpiller, Collins Denny material
    - Seigle-Hotsenpiller-Denny, Collins Denny material
    - Seigle etc., Collins Denny material
    - Seigle-Hotsenpiller bounty land, photostats
    - Seigle-Hotsenpiller family trees, Collins Denny material
    - Jacob and Milly - Sources, Seigle-Hotsenpiller
    - Children of Jacob and Miller - Sources, Seigle-Hotsenpiller
    - Jacob and Milly - Draft of Ms for book, Seigle-Hotsenpiller
    - Seigle-Hotsenpillar and Vann personal memorandum
  - (Box 16)
    - Simison
    - Grant J. Smith, Princess Anne, Va., a descendant of John P. Hotzinpiller
    - Surbaugh
    - John Adam Surbaugh, 5th generation
    - Surbaugh correspondents
    - Surbaugh descendants
    - Switzer and Bumgardner, 1897
    - Mary Elizabeth Hubbard Todd, Judith Hubbard Guthrie
    - Unanswered letters
    - Utterback
    - Elizabeth C. D. Vann and Margaret D. Dixon
    - Virginia Claims and Sessions, an unpublished thesis re: The Virginia Military District
    - Ohio Walter
  - (Box 17)
    - Mrs. Burton Wands
    - Wax family
    - Revolutionary Walter's sons
    - Susan Ellen Gaither Warren
    - Rebecca Lockhart Wright
    - Rebecca Lockhart Wright, 2 and 3
    - Printed Material
      - Fruit of the Song, 1976, Verse Writers Guild of Ohio
      - Hatzenbuhl und seine drei Kirchen
      - Iron Mining and Working and a Family of Halls, by Sophia Hall Glidden
      - Iron Institute
      - Iron, Ore and Adventure. Eisen, Erz und Abenteuer.
      - Ohio, Records and Pioneer Families, by Esther Powell
      - Ohio Poetry Day, 1973
  - (Box 18)
    - Virginia's First German Colony [Germanna] by Elizabeth C. D. Vann and Margaret C. D. Dixon
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Queen Anne Proof Sheet
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Lt. Gov. Spotswood, Proof Sheet
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Siegen, Germany Proof Sheet
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Germanna Sketch, Proof Sheet
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Iron Making, Proof Sheet 1
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Iron Making, Proof Sheet 2
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Iron Making, Proof Sheet 3
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Iron Making, Proof Sheet 4
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Germantown, Proof sheet
  - (Box 19)
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Rolling Road, from King's The Great South, Proof Sheet
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Hatzenbuhl, Germany, Proof Sheet
    - Germanna Pamphlet, Muesen, Germany, Proof Sheet
    - Germanna Reunion Picnics, 1958, 1960, Proof Sheet
    - William R. Denny, Proof Sheet
    - Hotsenpiller Family, Proof Sheet
    - Jacob Hotsenpiller and Miller Seigle, 1793 Marriage Bond, Proof Sheet
    - Final Page Proof, Book I, Denny Genealogy
  - (Box 20)
    - Address Books
    - Address Books, 1961-1962
    - Appointment Books, 1963-1964, Margaret Denny Dixon
    - Germanna Account Book, DAR Subscriptions to Virginia's First German Colony
    - Subscriptions to Denny Genealogies
    - Half-tone cuts/pictures
  - File Card Boxes
    - (Box 21)
      - Address Cards, Denny Genealogy, Book III, A-L
    - (Box 22)
      - Address Cards, Denny Genealogy, Book III, Mc-Z
    - (Box 23)
      - Address Cards, Denny Descendants, A-Z
    - (Box 24)
      - Address Cards, Denny Descendants, A-Z
    - (Box 25)
      - Address Cards, Hotsenpiller Descendants
    - (Box 26)
      - Bibliography, Denny Address Cards, A-Z
    - (Box 27)
      - Library subscriptions and reviewers for the Vann-Dixon genealogy books and the pamphlet
    - (Box 28)
      - Hotsenpiller Research Notes
  - (Box 103)
    - Melchior Brumbach Genealogical Chart
    - Denny Genealogical Chart, Coat of Arms, and Photographs
    - Renick Genealogical Chart